MILES MARTIN MORAN

1838 Quarley Pl., Henderson NV milesmoran2018@gmail.com
miles-m-moran | • milesmoran

SUMMARY

I like to say that, if I were a superhero, I would be an empath. As a tutor at a community college, I've taught old men how to multiply and divide. As a student at UNR, I've met ELL students who can perform advanced calculus in their heads. This incredible diversity of the people I've worked with (and for) has fostered – simultaneously – my love of mathematics, and my love of meeting new people. Although I've honed my analytical thinking skills through theory-intense projects, I know I can always improve when given the opportunity to bounce ideas off of another bright mind.

EDUCATION

APPLIED MATHEMATICS, BSc., UNIVERSITY OF NEVADA, RENO

DEC 2018 - MAY 2020

• Graduated with a 3.98 Major GPA, equivalent to High Honors

EXPERIENCE

STUDENT GRADER, UNIVERSITY OF NEVADA, RENO

JAN 2020 - MAY 2020

- Provided clear and succinct feedback on homework assignments pertaining to Statistical Theory
- · Identified areas of improvement for a class of 30 students & directed them to the proper resources

EVENT SUPPORT TECHNICIAN / STAGEHAND, UNIVERSITY OF ROCHESTER

AUG 2018 - DEC 2018

- Aided in the organization and running of 100+ events over the course of the semester
- Designed and implemented audio/video accompaniment for some of the university's largest ceremonies
- Achieved basic proficiency with lighting and sound systems common in theater (and similar stage events)
- · Learned how to communicate swiftly and efficiently under pressing constraints (e.g. strictly nonverbal)

MATHEMATICS TUTOR, COLLEGE OF SOUTHERN NEVADA

AUG 2017 - AUG 2018

- Utilized professional techniques (e.g. Redirecting Questions) to help students attain self-sufficiency
- Stayed after hours as-needed to ensure certain struggling / at-risk students got the help they needed
- Recruited 2 employees from my college program, and acted as an advisor / role model in their on-boarding
- · Spearheaded the department's use of (fun) monthly reflection activities between tutors and supervisors

SBI PROGRAM / SERVICE FACILITATION INTERN, CLARK COUNTY HUMAN RESOURCES JUN 2016 - Aug 2016

- Helped arrange and host a public forum between Las Vegas residents and their local police department
- Managed outreach to local businesses (grocers, etc.) to raise over \$1,000 in supplies
- · Articulated, troubleshot, and solved hardware (e.g. printer) malfunctions

SKILLS

Programming Languages *Experienced:* Python | R *Familiar:* Java | C++ | SQLite

Frameworks & Libraries MatPlotLib | Numpy | Pandas | SciKit-Learn

Record Keeping LaTeX | Git | MS Word | MS Excel

Research Interests Statistical Learning | Computer Vision | Stochastic Processes

ACTIVITIES _

COUNSELOR, NEVADA BOYS' STATE PROGRAM

2017 - 2019

Created and assessed programming schedules for a students' mock-government camp

DIRECTOR'S APPRENTICE, T.O.O.P. THEATER COMPANY

2018 - 2018

• Collaborated with student actors to stage a club theater production